Guide to the Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
- R
  - ___________. "Studies upon the keeping quality of butter." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1904. (Box 4)
  - Ross, Mary J. "The origin and development of the gastric glands of desmognathus amblystoma and pig." Reprinted from Biological Bulletin, December 1902. (Box 4)
  - Russel, H.L. "A lesson in bovine tuberculosis." University of Wisconsis Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 114, June 1904. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Tuberculosis and the tuberculin test." University of Wisconsis Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 40, July 1894. (Box 4)
  - Rutherford, J.G. " The control of bovine tuberculosis." A paper read before Section VII. Of the International Congress on Tuberculosis at Washington, D.C., 1 October 1908. (Box 4)
- S
  - Salisbury, G.W. "A controlled experiment in feeding wheat germ oil as a supplement to the normal ration of bulls used for artificial insemination." Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, July 1944. (Box 4)
  - ________, D.W. Baker, and J.W. Britton."Control of Equine Strongylosis, Part 2." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1940. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Recent research developments in the preservation and handling of bovine semen." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1941. (Box 4)
  - ________ and R.W. Bratton. "Fertility level of bull semen diluted at 1:400 with and without sulfanilamide." Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, September 1948. (Box 4)
  - ________, Irvine Elliott, and N.L. Van Demark. "Further studies of the effect of dilution rate on the fertility of bull semen used for artificial insemination. Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, March 1945. (Box 4)
  - ________, H.K. Fuller and E.L. Willett. "Preservation of bovine spermatozoa in yolk-citrate diluent and field results from its use. Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, November 1941. (Box 4)
  - ________, C.B. Knodt and R.W. Bratton. "The freezing point depression of bull semen and its relation to the diluter problem." Reprinted from Journal of Animal Science, August 1948. (Box 4)
  - ________ and Ernest Mercier. "The reliability of estimates of the proportion of morphologically abnormal spermatozoa in bull semen. Reprinted from Journal of Animal Science, May 1945. (Box 4)
  - ________ and N. L. Vandemark. "Stimulation of livability and glycolysis by additions of glucose to the egg yolk-citrate diluent for ejaculated bovine semen." Reprinted from The American Journal of Physiology, May 1945. (Box 4)
  - ________ and E.L. Willett. "An artificial vagina for controlled-temperature studies of bull semen." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, January 1940. (Box 4)
  - ________, E.L. Willett and Jack Seligman. "The effect of the method of making semen smears upon the number of morphologically abnormal spermatozoa." Reprinted from Journal of Animal Science, August 1942. (Box 4)
  - ________, I.A. Zelaya and N. L. Vandemark. "Livibility and glycolysis of bovine spermatozoa in yolk-citrate, incubated eggs or chick-embryo diluters. Reprinted from Journal of Animal Science, August 1945. (Box 4)
  - ________, et al. "Rapid methods for estimating the number of spermatozoa in bull semen. Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, January 1943. (Box 4)
  - ________, et al. "The effect of dilution rate on the livability and the fertility of bull spermatozoa used for artificial insemination. Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, November 1943. (Box 4)
  - Salmon, Daniel E. "Bureau of Animal Industry." Reprinted from Yearbook of Department of Agriculture, 1897. (Box 4)
  - __________. "Cornstalk disease and rabies in cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1896. (Box 4)
  - __________. "Legislation with reference to bovine tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 28, 1901. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Report of the chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry for 1897." From the Secretary of Agriculture, 1897. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Reports on bovine tuberculosis and public health." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 53, 1904. (Box 4)
  - _______. "The tuberculin test of imported cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1901. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Tuberculosis of the food-producing animals." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 38, 1906. (Box 4)
  - ________. "Wheat as a food for growing and fattening animals." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry. (Box 4)
  - ________and CH. Wardell Stiles. "Scab in sheep." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1903. (Box 4)
  - Sanarelli, J. "The etiology and pathogenesis of yellow fever." Reprinted from International Medical Magazine, 15 January 1898. (Box 4)
  - Sanderson, Dwight. "A Survey of sickness in rural areas in Cortland County, New York." Memoir 112, 24 January 1927. (Box 4)
  - Santamarina, Victor. "Artritis reumatoidea propiamente dicha." La Habana, Cuba, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Savage, A., W.W. Williams and N.M. Fowler. "A Statistical Study of the head length variability of bovine spermatazoa and its application to the determination of fertility." From the Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, 1927. (Box 4)
  - Savage, A., W.W. Williams and N.M. Fowler. "A study of the head length variability of equine spermatozoa." Canadian Journal of Research, 1930. (Box 4)
  - Savage, E.S. "Computing Rations for Farm Animals." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Statoin of the College of Agriculture Department of animal Husbandry Bulletin, No 321, October 1912. (Box 4)
  - Schalk, A.F. "Undulant fever in man and its relationship to abortion disease in cattle and swine." Agricultural Experiment Station North Dakota Agricultural College, April 1930. (Box 4)
  - ______ and R.S. Amadon. "Physiology of the ruminant stomach." Agricultural Experiment Station, North Dakota Agricultural College Bulletin, No. 216, February 1928. (Box 4)
  - Schering & Glatz. "Formalin." ca. 1893 (Box 4)
  - Schneider, L. "Passive immunitat der gegn die geflugelpest immunen kucken des haushuns." Reprinted from Acta Veterinaria, November 1950. (Box 4)
  - Schroeder, E.C. and W.E. Cotton. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 52, pt. 3, 1905. (Box 4)
  - ______ and W.E. Cotton. "Experiments with milk artifically infected with tubercle bacilli." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 86, 1906. (Box 4)
  - ______ and W.E. Cotton. "The relation of tuberculous lesions to the mode of infection." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 93, 1906. (Box 4)
  - ______and W.E. Cotton. "Tubercle bacilli in butter: their occurrence, vitality, and significance." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 4 April 1908. (Box 4)
  - Schroeder, E.C. and John R. Mohler. "The tuberculin test of hogs and some methods of their infection with tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 88, 1906. (Box 4)
  - Seaman, W.H. "The essentials of good education, with a new classification of knowledge." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1891. (Box 4)
  - ________. "The Victoria Regia." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists. (Box 4)
  - Sears, Frederick W. "Some problems in rural hygiene." (Box 4)
  - Sedgwick, T.F. "Chickens and their diseases in Hawaii." Hawaii Agricultural Experiment Station, 1901. (Box 4)
  - Sharr, E. and Opalka. "A report on the bacteriological and physical examination of lung tuberculosis in cattle." State Board of Live Stock Commissioners of Illinois Bulletin No. 5, March 1912. (Box 4)
  - Shaw, Christopher C., et al. "Enhancement of penicillin blood levels in man by means of a new compound by means of a new compound, caronamide." Reprinted from The American Journal of Medicine, August 1947. (Box 4)
  - Shaw, Edward L. and Lewis L. Heller. "The management of sheep on the farm." Bulletin of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 17 December 1913. (Box 4)
  - Shookhoff, Charles and Leo M. Taran. "Electrocardiographic studies in infectious diseases: I. Normal Children. ." Reprinted from The American Journal of Diseases of Children, August 1931. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Electrocardiographic studies in infectious diseases: II. Scarlet fever." Reprinted from The American Journal of Diseases of Children, September 1931. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Electrocardiographic studies in infectious diseases: III. Diptheria" Reprinted from The American Journal of Diseases of Children, October 1931. (Box 4)
  - Shute, D.K. "Racial anatomical peculiarities." The American Anthropologist, April 1896. (Box 4)
  - Singer, Arnold J. and D.W. Baker. "Phenothiazine as an anthelmentic for intestinal nematode parasitisms in sheep." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1940. (Box 4)
  - Slavin, George. "Penicillin concentration in the blood and milk of bovines." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Royal Society of Medicine, October 1946. (Box 4)
  - Small, James Craig. "Streptococci in relation to rheumatic disease." (Box 4)
  - Smith, F.A. Upsher. "The international unit of digitalis." Reprinted from the Jounral of the Maerican Pharmaceutical Association, May 1931. (Box 4)
  - Smith, John A. "Cooperation in the control of communicable diseases among school children." New York State Department of Health, 1920. (Box 4)
  - Smith, Theobald. "Comparative pathology: Its relation to biology and medicine." Read before the Pathological Society of Philadelphia, 26 April 1900. (Box 4)
  - _______. Cow serum as a substitute for colostrum in new-norn calves." Reprinted from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1 October 1922. (Box 4)
  - _______, Ralph B. Little and Marian S. Taylor. "Further studies on the etiological role of vibrio fetus." Reprinted from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1 December 1920. (Box 4)
  - _______ and H.W. Graybill. "Epidemiology of blackhead in turkeys under approximately natural conditions." Reprinted from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1 December 1920. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Injuries to cattle from swallowing pointed objects." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 8, n.d. (Box 4)
  - _______. "One of the conditions under which discontinuous sterilization may be ineffective." Reprinted from The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1898. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Public health laboratories." Reprinted from the Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 15 November 1900. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Some biological and economic aspects of comparative pathology." Reprinted from the Edinburgh Medical Journal, April 1924. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Some problems in the life history of pathogenic microorganismz." Reprinted from American Medicine, 22 October 1904. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Theories of susceptibility and resistance in relation to methods of artifical immunization." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Institute of Medicine of Chicago, 1920-1921. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Undulant fever: its relation to new problems in bacteriology and public health." Medicine: Analytical Reviews of General Medicine, Neurology and Pediatrics, May 1929. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Zur kenntniss der amerikanischen schweineseuche." Reprinted from Zeitschrift fur Hygeine, 1891. (Box 4)
  - _______ and H.W. Graybill. "Blackhead in chieckens and its experimental production by feeding embryonated eggs of heterakis papillosa. Reprinted from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1 August 1920. (Box 4)
  - Smithburn, K.C. and J.M Masters. "The treatment of secondary anemia (especially with various preparations of iron)." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, June 1931. (Box 4)
  - Smithburn, K.C. and L.G. Zerfas. "The neural symptoms and signs in pernicious anemia." Reprinted from The Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, May 1931. (Box 4)
  - Snow, William F. "Clinices for venereal diseases: Why we need them; how to develop them." Reprinted from Social Hygiene, January 1917. (Box 4)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine. "Proceedings." February 1929. (Box 4)
  - Spori, H. "Veranderungen der systolendauer im elektrokardiogramm von rind und meerschweinchen." Reprinted from the Archiv fur wissenschaftliche und pracktische tierheilkunde, 1941. (Box 4)
  - _______ and W. Leeman. "Proriozeptive relexbradykardie beim pferd. Reprinted from the Schweizer Archiv fur Tierheilkunde, 1944. (Box 4)
  - Stader, Otto. "Suggested procedures for the treatment of fractures with the Statder reduction splint." Sun Instrument Company pamphet, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Stalker, M and W.B. Niles. "Investigation of bovine tuberculosis." Iowa Agricultural College Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 29, 1895. (Box 4)
  - Stanclift. Ray Jones. "Aseptic castration of male animals." Reprinted from American Veterinary Review, July 1898. (Box 4)
  - State Charities Aid Association of New York. "Prevention of tuberculosis [ Proceedings of a Meeting held in Harmanus Bleecker Hall, Albany January 27 1908]." 1908. (Box 4)
  - Steck, W. "Latent infection in mastitis." Eleventh International Veterinary Congress, London, 1930. (Box 4)
  - Stephenson, H.C. "Urinary Antiseptics." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1934-1934. (Box 4)
  - _______ and H.J. Milks. "Nembutal." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, Vol.XXI, No.2, April 1931. (Box 4)
  - Sternberg, George M. "Disinfection and individual prophylaxis against infectious diseases." American Public Health Association Lomb Prize Essay, 1900. (Box 4)
  - Stiles, Charles W. "Bau u. entwicklungsgeschichte v. pentastomum proboscideum rud. Und pentastomum subcylindricum dies." Reprinted from Zeitschrift dur wissenschaftliche Zoologique, 1891. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Notes on parasites: Myzomimus." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, February 1892. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Notes on parasites." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, March 1892. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Notes sure les parasites." Reprinted from the Bulletin de la Societe Zoologique, 1891. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Sur la biologie des linguatules." Reprinted from the Comptes rendus des senaces de la Societe de Biologie, May 1891. (Box 4)
  - Stone, Winthrop E. "The carbohydrates of wheat, maize, flour, and bread, and the action of enzymic ferments upon starches of different origin." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 34, 1896. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Dietary studies at Purdue University, Lafayette, IND., in 1895." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 32, 1896. (Box 4)
  - Stroud, Bert. B. "If an 'isthmus rhombencephali' why not an 'isthmus prosencephali'?" Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, December 1899. (Box 4)
  - _______. "The mammalian cerebellum, part 1." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, July 1895. (Box 4)
  - _______. "A new head-rest for the removal of the human brain." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, May 1900. (Box 4)
  - _______. "Notes on the appendix." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, December 1897. (Box 4)
  - _______. "On the anatomy of the anus." Reprinted from Annals of Surgery, July 1896. (Box 4)
  - _______. "A preliminary account of the degenerations in the central nervous system of frogs deprived of the cerebrum." Cornell reprint? (Box 4)
  - Sunderville, Earl S. "The location of the accessible lymph glands in cattle with reference to physical diagnosis." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York Veterinary College, 1913-1914. (Box 4)
  - _______. The Lymphatics of Cattle. Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York Veterinary College, n.d. (Box 4)
  - _______. A post mortem method with the anatomy of the domestic fowl." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York Veterinary College, 1927-1928. (Box 4)
  - _______. A post mortem method with the anatomy of the domestic fowl." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, October1928. (Box 4)
  - _______. (Box 4)
  - Swingle, Leroy D. "The morphology of the sheep tape-worm." University of Wyoming Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin, No. 102, January 1914. (Box 4)
  - Swingle, Walter T. "Bordeaux mixture: its chemistry, physical properties, and toxic effects on fungi and algae." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Vegetable Physiology and Pathology, Bulletin No. 9, 1896. (Box 4)
  - Szegedy-Maszak, E. de. "Les dernieres experiences sur la transmission des maladies animales chez l'homme (en tenant specialement compte des differents metiers)." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 4)
  - Szpilman, Josef. "Bekampfung und tilgung der wutkrankheit." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 4)
- T
  - Tanabe, T. and G.W. Salisbury. "The influence of age on breeding efficiency of dairy cattle in artificial insemination." Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, June 1946. (Box 5)
  - Taylor, Thomas. "Food products.-III." Reprinted with revision from the Report of the Secretary of Agriculture for 1891, 1893. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Report of the Chief of the Division of Microscopy for 1893." U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1894. (Box 5)
  - Taylor, Walter J. "The agglutination and precipitating power of glandered and non glandered blood serum in diagnosis." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association, September 1907. (Box 5)
  - _______ and Wm. H. Boynton. "Gid found in sheep." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1908-1909. (Box 5)
  - Todd, L. C. "Comparative study of bacillus anthracis-symptomatici and allied organisms with respect to gas-production." Parke-Davis Research Laboratory, Reprint No. 118, 1917. (Box 5)
  - Traum, B.S. Henry and C.M. Haring. "Methods for the isolation of Brucella Abortus." Reprinted from Hilgarida, January 1932. (Box 5)
  - Troy, H.C. Alpha and beta lactose in some milk products." Reprinted from the Journal of Dairy Science, March 1930. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The babcock test." Khaki University of Canada, n.d. (Box 5)
  - _______. "A cheese moisture test." Cornell Extension Bulletin No 17, May 1917. (Box 5)
  - _______. "A comparison of fat tests in milk as determined by a cow-testing association and by a creamery." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No 400, January 1920. (Box 5)
  - _______ and T.J. McInerney. "Dairy laboratory exercises on milk composition and tests." New York State College of Agriculture, 3rd ed.1930. (Box 5)
  - _______and T.J. McInerney. "Dairy laboratory exercises on testing and composition of dairy products." New York State College of Agriculture, 1st ed.1922. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Methods of testing and of determining relative values of milk." Cornell Extension Bulletin No 116, June 1925. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Physical factors influencing the formation and fat content of gravity cream." Reprinted from the Journal of Dairy Science, May 1928." (Box 5)
  - _______ and Paul F. Sharp. "Quantitative determination of lactic acid in butter." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Memoir 202, March 1937. (Box 5)
  - Twelfth International Veterinary Congress, New York, August 1934. Complete set of reprints. (Box 5)
- U
  - Udall, D.H. "A report on the outbreak of 'cerebro-spinal meningitis'(encephalitis) in horses in Kansas and Nebraska in 1912." Reprinted from Cornell Veterinarian, June 1913. (Box 5)
  - Underhill, Frank. P. "The alleged toxin of burned skin." Reprinted fom The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931. (Box 5)
  - University of California, College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station. "Bovine infectious abortion and associated disease of cattle and new-born calves." Bulletin No. 353, January 1923. (Box 5)
- V
  - Vaillant, D. E. "La bacillosine." 3rd Congres Français de Climatotherapie & D'Hygiene Urbaine, April 1907. (Box 5)
  - Vandemark, N. L. and G.W. Salisbury. "The concentration of some B vitamins in bull semen." Reprinted from The Journal of Biological Chemistry, November 1944. (Box 5)
  - Vandemark, N. L., Ernest Mercier and G.W. Salisbury. "The methylene-blue reduction test and its relation to other measures of quality in bull semen." Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, February 1945. (Box 5)
  - Van Dine, D. L. "Insecticides for use in Hawaii." Hawaii Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 3, 1903. (Box 5)
  - Van Es, L. "Avian tuberculosis." North Dakota Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 108, April 1914. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Bovine tuberculosis." North Dakota Agricultural College, Government Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 77, July 1907. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Glanders." North Dakota Agricultural College, Government Agricultural Experiment Station of North Dakota, Bulletin No. 85, September 1909. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Notes on parasitic anaphylaxis and allergy." North Dakota Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 125, October 1917. (Box 5)
  - _______. and H. M. Martin. "The immunizing value of commercial vaccines and bacterins against herorrhagic septicemia." Agricultural Experiment Station, University oof Nebraska, Lincoln, Research Bulletin 17, June 1920. (Box 5)
  - Van Slyke, D. D. et al. "Observations on the courses of different types of Bright's Disease, and on the resultant changes in renal anatomy." Reprinted from Medicine, September 1930. (Box 5)
  - Van Slyke, L. L. And J. C. Baker. "Conditions causing variation in the reaction of freshly-drawn milk." New York Agricultural Experiment Station, Technical Bulletin No. 70, June 1919. (Box 5)
  - Voltz, W. "Stallfutterung und weidegang vom biologischen gesichtpunkte." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 5)
  - Voorhees, Edward B. "Food and nutrition investigations in New Jersey in 1895 and 1896." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 35, 1896. (Box 5)
- W
  - Wait, Charles E. "Dietary studies at the University of Tennessee in 1895. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 29, 1896. (Box 5)
  - Wallace, A. W. "Sino-auricular block" Reprinted from American Heart Journal, April 1930. (Box 5)
  - Walter Reed Memorial Association. [Yellow Fever Epidemics]. ca. 1903 (Box 5)
  - Ward, Archibald R. "Fowl cholera." University of California, College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 156, April 1904. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Tuberculosis in fowls." University of California College of Agriculture /Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 161, 1904. (Box 5)
  - _______ and Frederick Willan Wood. " Simultaneous method of inoculating cattle and carabaos with serum from animals that have been recently immunized." Reprinted from The Philippine Journal of Science, February 1914. (Box 5)
  - Ward, Herbert C. "Blackleg agressin." Reprinted from Journal of American Veterinary Medical Association, July 1919. (Box 5)
  - Way, Cassius. "Practical application of the agglutination method for the diagnosis of glanders." American Veterinary Review, September 1907. (Box 5)